# **Shawn Walton**



sh@wn.zone



(630) 618-0280



linkedin.com/in/shawn-walton-7582838a



https://sha.wn.zone

## Summary

Experienced full-stack web engineer trained in React, Python, high-performance compute, and a smidge of machine learning looking to make a real difference in the world. 5 years of experience building, refining, and perfecting a high-traffic, complex web page from backend to frontend.

## **Experience**

## Senior Software Engineer

Yelp

Aug 2016 - Present (4 years 11 months +)

Full stack web engineer on the SearchUX team.

- Delivered dozens of user-facing features, working with product, design, and fellow engineers
- Identified and fixed hundreds of milliseconds worth of performance issues
- Co-architected a backend migration to GraphQL
- Worked closely with designers to implement a full-page redesign
- Played an instrumental role in converting the desktop web search page from jQuery/ES5 to React/ ES6+
- Organized several successful team offsites
- Ran dozens of site deploys, coordinating 15-20 people and large-scale infrastructure

## **Web Development Intern**

**TigerConnect** 

Jun 2015 - Aug 2015 (3 months)

Worked on TigerText's single-page web messaging app, administrator interface, and Node.JS backend.

## Software Engineering Intern

Dow

Feb 2014 - May 2015 (1 year 4 months)

Designing and building internal HTML5 webapps to support the Dow Coatings business as well as research and design with the latest interactive hardware

#### **Education**



### University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign

Bachelor of Science (BS), Computer Science

2012 - 2016

Focused on high performance computing using CUDA, OpenMP, and MPI, with a minor in Astronomy.

#### Skills

C • OpenCL • Python • CUDA • Java • JavaScript • React.js • GraphQL • HTML5 • Splunk